Frederick A. Weiss Papers
Frederick A. Weiss Papers
1926-1963
Weiss, Frederick A.
3.5 linear feet
Papers of the American psychologist and author. Collection includes reprints of articles, notes, and typescripts; most articles appeared in the American Journal of Psychoanalysis.
148742
Biographical History
Frederick A. Weiss was an American psychologist and author. Among other things he wrote several essays on German psychoanalyst Karen Horney.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Frederick A. Weiss Papers consists entirely of writings by Weiss, including reprints of journal articles, lectures, and papers by Dr. Weiss. There are also two published volumes and a few handwritten notes.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by title of the publication in which it appeared, and within that chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Science and medicine; Weiss, Frederick A.; Psychoanalysis.; Psychoanalysts -- United States.; Psychologists -- United States.; Articles.; Lectures.; Notes (documents); Papers (document genres); Reprints.; Psychoanalysts.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Frederick A. Weiss, 1967, 1971.
Inventory
- Writings
  - Reprints
    - American Journal of Psychiatry
      - Volume VI, 1946 (Box 1)
      - Volume X, 1950; 7 folders (Box 1)
      - Volume XII, 1952; 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Volume XIV, 1954; 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Volume XVI, 1956; folders (Box 1)
      - Volume XVII, 1957; 1 folders (Box 1)
      - Volume XVII, 1957; 5 folders (Box 2)
      - Volume XVIII, 1958; 6 folders (Box 2)
      - Volume XIX, 1959; 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Volume XX, 1960; 1 folders (Box 2)
      - Volume XX, 1960; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Volume XXI, 1961; 4 folders (Box 3)
      - Volume XXII, undated; folders (Box 3)
      - Volume XXIII, undated; folders (Box 3)
      - Volume XXIV, undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Volume XXV, undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Volume XXVI, undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Volume XXVI, undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Association for the Advancement of Psychoanalysis, 1948 (Box 4)
    - Science and Psychoanalysis, 1963 (Box 4)
    - The Woman, 1942 (Box 4)
    - Various lectures and papers, 1947-1961 (Box 4)
  - Magazines
    - Folia Medici, 1935-1938 (Box 5)
  - Notes
    - Miscellaneous notes and typescripts, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Books
    - Almanach, 1926 (Box 5)
    - Almanach der Psychoanalyse, 1932 (Box 5)